smokefree.nhs.uk 2018-11-24

# Privacy and cookies | Smokefree

## **PLEASE READ THIS PRIVACY POLICY CAREFULLY BEFORE USING THIS SITE**

Public Health England, an executive agency of the Department of Health ("We") are committed to protecting and respecting your privacy.

This policy (together with our terms of use Please see our [Terms and Conditions page] and any other documents referred to in it) sets out the basis on which any personal data we collect from you, or that you provide to us, will be processed by us. Please read the following carefully to understand our views and practices regarding your personal data and how we will treat it. By visiting any Public Health England website you are accepting and consenting to the practices described in this policy.

For the purpose of the Data Protection Act 1998 (the Act), the data controller is the Department of Health of:

Room 7N Wellington House

133-155 Waterloo Road

London

SE1 8UG

Our nominated representative for the purpose of the Act is Mr Gary Kemp.

## Information we may collect from you

We may collect and process the following data about you:

**Information you give us.** You may give us information about you by filling in forms on Public Health England websites (our sites) or by corresponding with us by phone, e-mail or otherwise. This includes information you provide when you register to use our site, subscribe to our service, participate in discussion boards (or other social media functions on or linked to our websites), enter a competition, promotion or survey or carry out any other activity and when you report a problem with our site. The information you give us may include your name, address, e-mail address and phone number, personal description, and any other information you provide.

**Information we collect about you.** With regard to each of your visits to our site we may automatically collect the following information:

  * technical information, including the Internet Protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, your login information, browser type and version, time zone setting, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform;
  * information about your visit, including the full Uniform Resource Locators (URL) clickstream to, through and from our site (including date and time); products you viewed or searched for; page response times, download errors, length of visits to certain pages, page interaction information, and methods used to browse away from the page and any phone number used to call our customer service number.

**Information we receive from other sources.** We may receive information about you if you use any of the other websites we operate or the other services we provide. In this case we will have informed you when we collected that data that it may be shared internally and combined with data collected on this site. We are also working closely with third parties (including, for example, business partners, sub-contractors in technical, delivery services, analytics providers, search information providers) and may receive information about you from them.

## Cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. For detailed information on the cookies we use and the purposes for which we use them see the section “Information about our use of Cookies” below.

### Uses made of the information

We use information held about you in the following way:

**Information you give to us.** We will use this information:

  * to carry out our obligations arising from any contracts entered into between you and us and to provide you with the information, products and services that you request from us;
  * to provide you with information about other Public Health England services we offer that we feel may be of interest to you, you can opt out of receiving any communication we send you relating to this at any time;
  * if you are an existing customer, we will only contact you by electronic means (e-mail or SMS) with information about services we feel may be of benefit to you. If you are a new customer, we will contact you by electronic means only if you have consented to this. If you do not want us to use your data in this way, please tick the relevant box situated on the form on which we collect your data (the registration form);
  * to notify you about changes to our service;
  * to ensure that content from our site is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer.

**Information we collect about you.** We will use this information:

  * to administer our site and for internal operations, including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, research, statistical and survey purposes;
  * to improve our site to ensure that content is presented in the most effective manner for you and for your computer;
  * to allow you to participate in interactive features of our service, when you choose to do so;
  * as part of our efforts to keep our site safe and secure;
  * to make suggestions and recommendations to you and other users of our site about services that may interest you or them.
  * to provide you with targeted advertising that we feel may be of interest to you. You are able to opt out of this at any time from here <http://radiumone.com/opt.html>

**Information we receive from other sources.** We may combine this information with information you give to us and information we collect about you. We may us this information and the combined information for the purposes set out above (depending on the types of information we receive).

### Disclosure of your information

We may share your personal information with any member of our group, which means our subsidiaries, our ultimate holding company and its subsidiaries, as defined in section 1159 of the UK Companies Act 2006.

We may share your information with selected third parties including:

  * Business partners, suppliers and sub-contractors for the performance of any contract we enter into with you.
  * Analytics and search engine providers that assist us in the improvement and optimisation of our site.

We may disclose your personal information to third parties:

  * If Public Health England or substantially all of its assets are transferred to a third party organisation, in which case personal data held by it about its customers will be one of the transferred assets.
  * If we are under a duty to disclose or share your personal data in order to comply with any legal obligation, or in order to enforce or apply our terms of use [Please see our Terms and Conditions page] and other agreements; or to protect the rights, property, or safety of Public Health England, our customers, or others.

### Where we store your personal data

 All information you provide to us is stored on our secure servers held in England only. Where we have given you (or where you have chosen) a password which enables you to access certain parts of our site, you are responsible for keeping this password confidential. We ask you not to share a password with anyone.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Although we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot guarantee the security of your data transmitted to our site; any transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use strict procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

### Your rights

You have the right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes. We will usually inform you (before collecting your data) if we intend to use your data for such purposes or if we intend to disclose your information to any third party for such purposes. You can exercise your right to prevent such processing by checking certain boxes on the forms we use to collect your data.  You can also exercise the right at any time by contacting us at **smokefree@phe.gov.uk**

Our site may, from time to time, contain links to and from the websites of our partner networks and affiliates.  If you follow a link to any of these websites, please note that these websites have their own privacy policies and that we do not accept any responsibility or liability for these policies.  Please check these policies before you submit any personal data to these websites.

### Access to information

The Act gives you the right to access information held about you. Your right of access can be exercised in accordance with the Act.

### Changes to our privacy policy

Any changes we may make to our privacy policy in the future will be posted on this page and, where appropriate, notified to you by email. Please check back frequently to see any updates or changes to our privacy policy.

### Contact

Questions, comments and requests regarding this privacy policy are welcomed and should be addressed to

Mr Gary Kemp

Department of Health

Wellington House

133-155 Waterloo Road

London

SE1 8UG

## Information about our use of cookies

Our website uses cookies to distinguish you from other users of our website. This helps us to provide you with a good experience when you browse our website and also allows us to improve our site. By continuing to browse the site, you are agreeing to our use of cookies.

A cookie is a small file of letters and numbers that we store on your browser or the hard drive of your computer if you agree. Cookies contain information that is transferred to your computer's hard drive.

We use the following cookies:

  * **Strictly necessary cookies.** These are cookies that are required for the operation of our website. They include, for example, cookies that enable you to log into secure areas of our website.
  * **Analytical/performance cookies.** They allow us to recognise and count the number of visitors and to see how visitors move around our website when they are using it. This helps us to improve the way our website works, for example, by ensuring that users are finding what they are looking for easily.
  * ScorecardResearch use information collected through these cookies to help RadiumOne (please see the Advertising cookies section below) understand how widely its advertising services are used on the Internet. To refuse these ScorecardResearch cookies, please visit: <http://scorecardresearch.com/optout.aspx>
  * **Functionality cookies.** These are used to recognise you when you return to our website. This enables us to personalise our content for you, greet you by name and remember your preferences (for example, your choice of language or region).
  * **Targeting cookies.** These cookies record your visit to our website, the pages you have visited and the links you have followed. We will use this information to make our website more relevant to your interests. We may also share this information with third parties for this purpose.
  * **Advertising cookies.**
  * **RadiumOne** \- This cookie allows our service provider, RadiumOne, to collect information when you use its 'Po.st' sharing tool to share links to pages or content on our sites. RadiumOne uses this information to identify the interests of users who share Po.st links and also users who click on those links, so that we can deliver advertising that is more relevant to your and their interests. For more information on RadiumOne and its privacy practices, please visit: <http://radiumone.com/about/privacy.html>. If you would like to refuse these RadiumOne cookies at any time, please visit: <http://www.radiumone.com/about/privacy.html#opting_out>
  * AppNexus - This is a technology platform (Platform or AppNexus Platform) that we use to buy, sell, and deliver online advertising, including interest-based advertising, mostly through real-time bidding. In other words, the AppNexus Platform does not itself buy, sell, or deliver ads, but provides technology that other companies use for those purposes. The AppNexus Platform is designed to enable other companies (their clients) to buy, sell, or deliver advertising using “Platform Data” that clients may collect using the Platform, derive from their use of the Platform, or acquire from other sources and then use on the Platform. For more information on AppNexus and its cookie policy, please visit: <http://www.appnexus.com/en/company/cookie-policy>. You can click below to opt out of having the Platform used to select ads for your browser based on your online web browsing behaviour. When you opt out, an opt out cookie (from adnxs.com) will be stored in your web browser. The Platform will know the choice you have made when it sees your opt out cookie, and will apply your choice to all companies’ use of the Platform. If you block or delete the opt out cookie, the Platform will not see your choice. If you would like to refuse these AppNexus cookies at any time, please visit: <http://www.appnexus.com/en/company/platform-privacy-policy#choices>

The opt out cookie may not work if your browser is configured to block third-party cookies. If you delete your cookies, you will need to opt out again. There are browser plugins to help you preserve your opt out cookies. For more information, please visit <http://www.aboutads.info/PMC>

The opt out only applies to the browser in which you set it. For example, if you set the opt out while using Firefox, but then use Chrome, the opt out will not be active in Chrome. To opt out in Chrome, you will need to repeat the opt out process.

The opt out does not block or delete cookies, or prevent the use of cookies or other technologies for purposes other than selecting ads based on your interests as inferred by your online behaviour. If you opt out, data may still be collected about your web browsing activities and you will still see advertising. Ads may be selected, for example, based on the content of the web page in which they are shown. If you wish to block or delete cookies altogether, you can use web browser settings to do so.

Please note that third parties (including, for example, providers of external services like web traffic analysis services) may also use cookies, over which we have no control. These cookies are likely to be analytical/performance cookies or targeting cookies.

You block cookies by activating the setting on your browser that allows you to refuse the setting of all or some cookies. However, if you use your browser settings to block all cookies (including essential cookies) you may not be able to access all or parts of our site.

To find out how to allow, block, delete and manage the cookies on all standard web browsers, please go to [www.aboutcookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/) 

If you use a mobile phone to browse our websites or other sites that use cookies, please refer to your handset manual for guidance.
